- So, what do you do? - I'm studying to be an actress. You?
- 那你是做什麼的？ - 我正在學習表演，你呢？
- I'm a longshoreman. - No, I mean, really.
- 我在碼頭做搬運工 - 認真說啦
I mean really, too.
我是認真說的
Although, starting next Monday,
不過下週一開始
I'm doing something a little more glamorous.
我會換一份更體面的工作
What's that?
是什麼？
Night cashier at a cafeteria.
自助餐廳的夜間收銀員
I don't mean how you make money. I mean, what are you interested in?
我不是問你靠什麼餬口 你真正感興趣的是什麼？
Honey, if I had the answer to that one,
親愛的，要是我回答了這個問題
I bet I'd bore us both to death in half an hour.
你我一定都會無聊透頂
Thank God that's over.
謝天謝地總算是完了
So much for the debut of the Laurel Players.
這就是月桂劇團的處女秀
And she was very disappointing.
她看起來很失望
- Frank! Very nice, Frank! - Thanks so much, Mrs Givings.
- 弗蘭克！很精彩呀，弗蘭克！ - 多謝，吉文斯太太
I can't tell you how much we enjoyed it. You have a very talented wife.
我們真是陶醉其中了 你太太真是太有天分了
I'll pass it along.
我會轉告她的
- Frank! - Hi!
- 弗蘭克！ - 你好！
She's in there. I'm about ready for that drink.
她在裡面，我已經準備好喝酒了
Couple of minutes.
等幾分鐘
April? Sweetheart?
艾波爾？親愛的？
- You about ready to leave? - Yeah. Yeah.
- 準備走了嗎？ - 嗯
I've just got to get this makeup off.
等我先卸妝
Well, I guess it wasn't a triumph or anything, was it?
看樣子不是很成功啊，是麼？
- I guess not. I'll be ready in a minute. - Take your time.
- 不算是，我一會兒就好 - 不急
Listen, will you do me a favour?
對了，幫我個忙好嗎？
Milly and Shep wanted us to go out with them after.
米莉和薛普想和我們一起去慶祝
Will you say we can't? Say it's because of the babysitter or something.
你能不能拒絕他們？ 就說是保姆之類的事情
Well, the thing is, I already said that we could.
可是我已經答應他們了
I mean, I just saw them and I said that we would.
剛才看到他們了，我就答應了
Then would you mind going out again and saying you were mistaken?
那你能不能出去告訴他們你搞錯了？
That should be simple enough.
這應該不難吧
Don't you think that's a little bit rude, April?
你不覺得這有點粗魯嗎，艾波爾？
- Then I'll tell them myself. - Okay. Okay. Take it easy.
- 那我自己去說 - 好好，別激動
All right? I'll tell them.
好嗎？我去說
I mean it, baby. You were the only person in that play.
說真的，寶貝，其他人和你比都黯然失色
Thank you.
謝謝
We shouldn't have let you get mixed up in the damned thing, is all.
就不該讓你去和那幫人同台
All right.
行吧
What a bunch of amateurs. I mean, you've studied, for Christ's sake.
一群三腳貓，你可是專業的啊，天
Could we stop talking about it now?
能不能不說這個了？
Sure.
行
I just don't want you feeling bad about it, that's all.
我只是不想讓你難過
Because it's not worth it, you know.
你知道，這不值得
It's bad enough having to live out here amongst these people...
跟這些人混在一起真是糟…
- What'd you say? - I said yes. All right, Frank.
- 你剛說什麼？ - 我說對，弗蘭克
Could you just stop talking about it now before you drive me crazy, please?
你能不能在我抓狂之前閉嘴？
What are you doing?
你幹嘛？
April, sweetheart, let's talk about this, okay?
艾波爾，親愛的，好好說話行不？
- No, Frank, please don't do that. - Come on, now.
- 別，弗蘭克，別這樣 - 過來
- Don't touch me. - April...
- 別碰我 - 艾波爾…
Just leave me alone.
別理我
Okay. Okay.
好，好
It strikes me that there's a considerable amount of bullshit going on here.
我感覺現在的氣氛很不對勁
And there's just a few things that I'd like to clear up. All right?
我想澄清幾點，好嗎？
Number one, it's not my fault that the play was lousy. Okay?
第一，戲演的那麼差不是我的錯，對吧？
Number two, it sure as hell isn't my fault
第二，你沒能成為真正的演員
that you didn't turn out to be an actress,
也他媽的跟我沒關係
and the sooner you get over that little piece of soap opera,
你越早離開這些肥皂戲劇
the better off we're both going to be.
我們才能過得越好
Number three, I don't happen to fit the role
第三，我可不是那種愚蠢的
of dumb, insensitive suburban husband.
後知後覺的鄉村老公
You've been trying to lay that crap on me ever since we moved out here.
自從我們搬來之後 你就一直把錯推到我頭上
And I'm damned if I'll wear it.
我他媽的沒那麼笨
Number four... April? April!
第四…艾波爾？艾波爾！
April.
艾波爾
What the hell are you doing? Get back in the car.
你他媽的幹嗎？給我回車裡去
No. I will in a minute. Just let me stand here for a second.
不，等一下，讓我站一會兒
God damn it!
他媽的！
April, can you please just get back in the car and talk about this
艾波爾，能不能別大晚上站在12號公路上
instead of running all over Route 12?
我們回車裡談好嗎？
Haven't I made it clear I don't particularly want to talk about it?
我是不是沒說清楚？ 我不想談這件事
Okay. I mean, Jesus, I'm trying to be nice
好，看在上帝的份上
about this thing here, for God's sake.
我只是想跟你好好說話
How kind of you. How terribly, terribly kind of you.
你真好啊，你對我還真好啊
Wait a minute. I don't deserve this.
等等，你不該這麼對我
You're always so wonderfully definite
你總是很確定
on the subject of what you do and don't deserve.
自己該得到什麼，不該得到什麼
Wait a minute! Wait a goddamn... April! Now you listen to me.
等等！等…艾波爾！你給我聽著
This is one time you're not going to get away
這次你再也不能
with twisting everything that I say, April.
隨意歪曲我的本意了，艾波爾
This just happens to be one goddamn time
碰巧這次我很清楚
I know I'm not in the wrong here.
我絕沒有做錯什麼事
Christ, I wish you'd stayed home tonight.
天，真希望你今晚沒來
You know what you are when you're like this, April?
你知道自己現在什麼樣子嗎，艾波爾？
You're sick. I really mean that.
你病了，說真的
- You're sick! What? - And do you know what you are?
- 你病了！ - 你知道你什麼樣子嗎？
- You're disgusting. - Oh, yeah?
- 你真噁心 - 哦，是嗎？
You don't fool me, Frank.
別玩我了，弗蘭克
Just because you've got me safely in this little trap,
別以為你讓我呆在一個安全的陷阱裡
you think you can bully me into feeling whatever you want me to feel!
你就可以為所欲為地控制我的感情
- You in a trap? You in a trap? - Yes! Yes! Me, Frank!
- 你在陷阱裡？你在陷阱裡？ - 對！對！我是說我，弗蘭克！
- Jesus Christ, don't make me laugh! - Me!
- 老天爺，別逼我笑！ - 就是這樣！
You pathetic, self-deluded little boy. Look at you!
你這個自欺欺人的可憐蟲，看看你自己！
Look at you and tell me, how by any stretch of the imagination
看看自己，再告訴我
you can call yourself a man?
就你這樣也敢自詡為男人？
Damn it!
操！
Jesus Christ!
老天爺！
- Don't look at me like that, April. - Could we please go home now?
- 別這麼看著我，艾波爾 - 現在能回家了嗎？
Fifteenth floor.
十五樓到了
I'm going to need your help this morning, Old Scout.
今早我你得幫我，哥們
For the next few hours, you're to warn me of Bandy's every approach
一旦班迪靠近我，你就警告我
and you may need to shield me from public view
還有，萬一我肚子太餓了
in the likely event I void my stomach.
你得幫我多擋著
It's that bad.
真的很緊急
Good morning, Jack.
早上好，傑克
Nothing good about it, I assure you.
沒什麼好事的，我保證
Of course, I knew the moment you stepped off the train
當然，你一下火車，我就知道
what you were looking for.
你在找什麼樣的房子
A small remodelled barn, or a carriage house.
翻修的小穀倉，或者馬車房
And I just hate to be the one to tell you that sort of thing
我可不願意唱黑臉
just isn't available any more.
告訴你這種房子已經沒有了
But I don't want you to despair.
不過不要失望
There is one place up here I want to show you.
我要帶你去看一處房子
Now, of course, it isn't very desirable at this end.
當然了，這條路上沒什麼好房子
As you can see, Crawford Road is mostly these little cinder-blocky,
你們也看到了 克勞福德路上儘是這種煤渣房
pick-up trucky places, plumbers, carpenters,
住著一些水管工，木匠，貨車司機
little local people of that sort.
類似這種的本地人
But eventually...
不過往前走呢…
Eventually it leads up to Revolutionary Road, which is much nicer.
就到了革命路，這裡就好多了
Now, the place I want to show you
我要帶你們看的房子呢
is a sweet little house and a sweet little setting.
環境優美，小巧別緻
Simple, clean lines, good lawns, marvellous for children.
簡單整潔，很好的草坪 對小孩子再好不過了
It's just around this next curve.
拐個彎就到了
Now, you'll see it. There. See the little white one? Sweet, isn't it?
就在那裡 看到那個小白房了嗎？很不錯吧？
The perky way it sits there on its little slope? Charming, isn't it?
很精神地坐落在小坡上，迷人吧？
Oh, yes.
是啊
You wanted to see me?
你找我？
Came for you from Toledo this morning. This is the third one this month.
今早托萊多（港口城市）發來找你的 這是這個月第三次了
Sorry. I thought I'd taken care of...
抱歉，我以為已經弄好了…
I'm not prepared to have this conversation again, Frank.
我不想再和你說這種事了，弗蘭克
- You understand? - I was literally just getting into...
- 明白嗎？ - 我只不過是…
These folks in the provinces look up to us. We need to be efficient.
那裡的人很尊重我們 所以我們做事必須有效率
We can't have this kind of back and forth, and so forth.
不能老這麼反反覆覆
- It's just not efficient. Am I right? - Yes.
- 這樣很沒效率，是吧？ - 嗯
- What was that about? - Toledo.
- 什麼事？ - 托萊多
Branch manager wants a revised brochure
主管經理要求修改
for the conference on the Knox 500.
關於諾克斯500的會議的宣傳冊子
"It's just not efficient. Am I right? Am I right? Am I right?"
「這樣很沒效率？是吧？是吧？是吧？」
Sounds like a goodie.
跟老太婆似的
For God's sake. I don't even know what the Knox 500 does. Do you?
天，我都不知道諾克斯500是幹嘛的 你知道不？
Don't insult me.
別抬舉我了
If you'll look in the inactive file under SP 1109,
在SP 1109下面的待用文檔裡
you'll find copies of all the stuff we sent to the agency,
能找到我們發往代理商的所有文件副本
that way we can trace the thing back to its original sources.
這樣就能夠往回追溯到發件人了
Listen, I hope you weren't planning on having an early lunch.
聽著，你沒打算這麼早吃午飯吧
No. I'm not really hungry.
沒，我不是很餓
Good. I'll check on you later then. All right?
好，我回頭再來找你，好吧？
- Okay.
- 行 - 好
You know something, Maureen? You're lucky you met me.
知道嗎莫林，遇到我你算是走運了
How's that?
怎麼說？
I think I can show you the ropes, you know.
我可以告訴你竅門
There's a certain art to survival at Knox. Really. Let me show you what I mean.
想在諾克斯公司生存，要掌握一定的技巧 我演示給你看
Waiter. Bring me the telephone, would you? And two more martinis.
服務員，給我拿電話過來好嗎？ 再來兩瓶馬蒂尼
Wow.
哇
Klondike 5-55-66, please.
請接克朗代克55566
Hello, Mrs Jorgensen? Frank Wheeler here. Yes.
您好，約根森太太？我是弗蘭克·惠勒
I just wanted to let you know that I've had to send Maureen Grube
我就是想告訴您一聲 我把莫林·格魯德要了過來
down to Visual Aids for me.
做我的視覺助理
I'll probably need her the rest of the afternoon. Yes.
可能整個下午都需要她，對
You, too. Take care now.
您也一樣，午安
- I never even heard of Visual Aids. - That's because it doesn't exist.
- 我從沒聽說過什麼視覺助理 - 因為根本就不存在這個職位
Hi, Helen. Come on in.
你好，海倫，快請進
I can't stay a minute.
我就是路過
I just wanted to bring these sedum plantings
我給你帶了一些景天植物
for that messy patch down by the foot of the drive.
來點綴車道盡頭的那片地
It's like the European houseleek,
它跟歐洲石蓮花差不多
only these have the most marvellous little yellow blossoms.
不過會開很好看的小黃花
Now, all it wants for the first few days
只需要在開頭幾天
is just a tiny dollop of water, and then you'll find it absolutely thrives.
澆一點水，之後就能茁壯成長了
Well, thank you, Helen. That's so kind of you.
那謝謝你了，海倫，你人真好
Would you like some coffee?
要不要咖啡？
Is there something I can do for you, Helen?
有什麼需要我做的嗎，海倫？
I almost forgot.
我差點忘了
There is one small favour I would like to ask.
有一個不情之請
It's about... It's about my son, John. He's been in the hospital.
是我的…是我的兒子，約翰 他進醫院了
I'm sorry. Is everything all right?
很遺憾，都還好吧？
Well, actually, just for the time being, he's in Pleasant Brook. Psychiatric.
嗯，他現在暫時呆在 布萊森·布魯克，精神病院
- Oh, I see. - Well, it's nothing serious.
- 哦，我知道了 - 其實沒什麼大不了的
He just got a little run down. Things can just get the better of us sometimes.
小毛病，用不了多久就會好的
- Don't you agree? - Yes. Of course.
- 你說是吧？ - 嗯，當然
It's a marvellous facility
那裡條件很好
and the treatments seem to be doing wonders for him.
治療看起來也很有效
Anyway, they said getting him out for an afternoon
話說回來，醫生說讓他出來一下午
might do him a little bit of good.
也許對他會有好處
I think he finds my friends a little conventional, quite frankly.
坦白說，他覺得我的朋友們太保守了
I mean, he's travelled. He has a Ph.D. In mathematics.
他是見過世面的人，有數學博士學位
I suppose you could say he's an intellectual.
說他是個天才也不為過
It would do him a world of good to meet a young couple like you.
如果能讓他來見見你們夫婦 那真是再好不過了
Well, we'd love to meet him.
當然，我們很願意見他
- Really? - Yes.
- 真的？ - 是的
We'd love to.
很願意
Thank you, dear.
謝謝你，親愛的
Thank you.
謝謝
Well, I must be off.
好了，我得走了
I remember the first day you came off the train.
我記得你們剛下火車的那天
You weren't like my other clients. You were different.
你們跟我其他的客戶不一樣，很特別
You just seemed special.
一看就不是普通人
Of course, you still are.
當然了，現在還是
Remember, just a dollop. I must scoot. Toodle-oo.
記住，只要澆一點水，我走了先
Bye.
再見
I think you got me a little drunk.
我覺得有點醉了
You know what today is?
知道今天是什麼日子？
Monday?
星期一？
It's my birthday. I'm 30 years old today.
今天是我的生日，我三十歲了
- Happy birthday! - Thank you.
- 生日快樂！ - 謝謝
What was the name of that department you made up again?
你編的那個職位叫什麼來著？
Visual Aids.
視覺助理
What a joke.
真搞笑
- You want to hear a real joke? - Yes.
- 你想聽真正的笑話嗎？ - 嗯
- My old man worked at Knox. - Yeah?
- 我父親也曾在諾克斯工作 - 是嗎？
He was a salesman in Yonkers.
他在洋克斯市做銷售員
Once a year he used to take me into the city for lunch.
每年他都會帶我去城裡吃一次飯
It was supposed to be a very special, life-advice sort of occasion.
這個場合很特別，他會傳授點人生經歷之類的東西
- Nice. - No. Not really.
- 不錯啊 - 不，其實不然
I used to sit there and think,
每當那時侯，我總會想
"I hope to Christ I don't end up like you."
「老天，我長大了可別像你這樣」
Now, here I am, a 30-year-old Knox man.
現在看看我，三十歲的諾克斯員工
Can you beat that?
造化弄人啊
I think I kind of lost you...
我好像有點記不清楚了…
Your father worked for Knox?
你父親也在諾克斯工作？
I'm sorry, everything's just kind of going out of focus.
很抱歉，我有點集中不了精力了
Why don't we get some air, you and me?
不如我們出去透透氣？
Is this you?
這是你嗎？
Yeah.
對
- You been to Paris? - I've never really been anywhere.
- 你去過巴黎嗎？ - 我哪兒也沒去過
Maybe I'll take you with me then.
也許我可以帶你去
I'm going back the first chance I get, I tell you.
告訴你，一有機會我就會回巴黎去
People are alive there. Not like here.
那裡的人充滿活力，不像這裡
All I know, April, is I want to feel things.
我需要那種感受，艾波爾
Really feel them, you know.
那種真切的感受
How's that for an ambition?
我很有野心吧？
Frank Wheeler? I think you're the most interesting person I've ever met.
弗蘭克·惠勒？我覺得你是我見過的 最有意思的人
I guess this wasn't what you had in mind when you went to work this morning?
今早上班的時候沒想到會發生這種事吧？
No. It certainly wasn't.
沒，當然沒想到
Do you have a cigarette, Frank?
你有煙嗎，弗蘭克？
Yeah, sure.
當然有
There you go.
給你
Can I get you a drink or anything?
要不要喝點什麼？
No thanks, Maureen. Actually, it's...
不用了，謝謝，莫林 說實在的，現在…
It's getting kind of late. I guess I'd better be cutting out.
已經有點晚了，我得回去了
Gee, that's right. Did you miss your train?
哦對啊，你是不是錯過火車了？
That's all right, I'll catch the next one.
沒事的，我可以趕下一班
Listen, you were swell.
你看起來真美
Take care now.
保重
- Frank. - Why are you all dressed up?
- 弗蘭克 - 你穿這麼整齊幹嗎？
First of all, I missed you all day and I want to say I'm sorry.
首先，我今天很想你 我想跟你道歉
I'm sorry for the way I've been since the play.
我為演出之後的所作所為道歉
I'm sorry for everything, and I love you.
為所有那些事道歉，我愛你
The rest can wait.
其他先不說了
Now, you just wait here till I call you. Okay?
等我叫你再進來好嗎？
Okay.
好
All right, Frank. You can come in now.
好了弗蘭克，進來吧
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday, dear Daddy
祝親愛的老爸生日快樂
Happy birthday, darling.
祝你生日快樂，親愛的
- I love you, Daddy. - I love you, too.
- 我愛你，爸爸 - 我也愛你
Frank.
弗蘭克
Frank. I have had the most wonderful idea.
弗蘭克，我有個好主意
- I've been thinking about it all day. - Baby, what's all this about?
- 我今天一直在想 - 什麼主意，寶貝？
Do you know how much money we have saved?
你知道我們存了多少錢了嗎？
Enough to live on for six months without you earning another dime.
不用你上班，也夠用六個月
And with the money we could get from the house and the car, longer than that.
如果賣了車和房子，還能過更久
"What we could get for the house"?
「賣了房子」？
Sweetheart, what are you talking about? Where are we going to live?
親愛的，你說什麼呢？那我們住哪裡？
Paris.
巴黎
What?
什麼？
You always said it was the only place you'd ever been
你一直說，那是惟一一個
that you wanted to go back to, the only place that was worth living.
你願意再去的地方 唯一值得過日子的地方
So why don't we go there?
那我們為什麼不去呢？
- You're serious? - Yes. What's stopping us?
- 你說真的？ - 是啊，有什麼困難嗎？
What's stopping us? Well, I can think of a number of different things.
有什麼困難？我可以說出一堆來
For example, what kind of a job could I possibly get?
比如，去那裡我能做什麼？
You won't be getting any kind of a job, because I will.
不用你上班，因為我會有工作
Oh, right, right.
哦，是啊，是啊
Don't laugh at me. Listen a minute.
別笑我，聽我說
Do you know what they pay for secretarial positions
你知道政府給那些
- in government agencies in Europe? - No, I don't.
- 駐歐洲的秘書職位什麼薪水嗎？ - 不知道
Listen, Frank, I'm serious about this. Do you think I'm kidding or something?
聽著弗蘭克，我是認真說的 你以為我在開玩笑嗎？
Okay, okay. I just have a couple of questions, is all.
行，我只是有一些問題
For one thing, what exactly am I supposed to be doing
首先，要是你負責賺錢
while you're out earning all this money?
那我該幹什麼？
Don't you see? That's the whole idea.
你不明白嗎？關鍵就在於此
You'll be doing what you should've been allowed to do seven years ago.
你干你七年前想幹卻沒能幹成的事
You'll have time.
你會有很多時間
For the first time in your life you'll have time to find out
這會是你這輩子第一次有時間
what it is that you actually want to do.
思考自己該幹什麼
And when you figure it out,
當你想好以後
you'll have the time and the freedom to start doing it.
你還會有足夠的時間和自由去實現抱負
Sweetheart, it's just not very realistic, is all.
親愛的，這太不切實際了
No, Frank. This is what's unrealistic.
不，弗蘭克，我告訴你什麼才叫不切實際
It's unrealistic for a man with a fine mind to go on working
讓一個有理想的男人
year after year at a job he can't stand,
日復一日幹著他不想幹的工作
coming home to a place he can't stand,
回到一個他不願意呆的地方
to a wife who's equally unable to stand the same things.
面對一個同樣不能忍受這一切的老婆 這才是不切實際的
Do you want to know the worst part?
你知道最糟糕的是什麼嗎？
Our whole existence here is based on this great premise
我們自以為比周圍的人和事
that we're special and superior to the whole thing.
都來得特別，來得高貴
But we're not.
其實不是的
We're just like everyone else.
我們跟普通人一樣
Look at us. We've bought into the same ridiculous delusion.
你看看我們，理所當然的認為
This idea that you have to resign from life
有了孩子之後
and settle down the moment you have children.
就應該結束自己的生活，安頓下來
And we've been punishing each other for it.
我們一直因為這種荒唐的做法相互懲罰
Listen, we decided to move out here.
聽著，是我們倆自己決定搬到這裡
No one forced me to take the job at Knox.
沒人強迫我去諾克斯工作
I mean, whoever said I was meant to be a big deal, anyway?
再說了，誰說我有更重要的事去做？
When I first met you, there was nothing in the world you couldn't do or be.
第一次見到你時 你是個有著雄心壯志的人
When you first met me I was a little wise guy
第一次見到我時，我只是個耍小聰明的人
with a big mouth, that's all.
滿嘴忽悠，僅此而已
You were not. How can you even say that?
不是，你怎麼能這麼說自己？
Okay. Okay, so I'll have time.
好，我會有很多時間
And God knows that's appealing. It's very appealing.
誰都知道這很誘惑人，很誘惑
And everything you're saying makes sense
如果我有天分 如果我是個作家或者藝術家
if I had a definite talent, if I were a writer or an artist.
你設想的一切就說得通
No. But, Frank, listen. Listen to me.
不，弗蘭克，你聽我說
It's what you are that's being stifled.
真實的你被壓抑住了
It's what you are that's being denied and denied in this kind of life.
真實的你在這樣的生活中 被一次又一次否定
And what's that?
那我該是怎樣的？
Don't you know?
你不知道嗎？
You're the most beautiful and wonderful thing in the world.
你是這世間最美最好的人
You're a man.
你是個真男人
This is our chance, Frank. This is our one chance.
這是我們的機會，弗蘭克，我們的機會
Okay.
好
Okay?
好？
Why not? Why the hell not?
為何不呢？何樂而不為呢？
- Good morning, all. - Morning, Frank.
- 早上好，各位 - 早安，弗蘭克
Franklin. Good to see your shining face.
弗蘭克，很高興看到你燦爛的笑容
- What's the news? - Fellas, I'm moving to Paris.
- 有什麼好消息？ - 夥計們，我要搬去巴黎了
Indeed. And I'm moving to Tangiers.
是嗎，那我要搬去丹吉爾了 （摩洛哥城市）
Intra-company letter to Toledo.
發往托萊多的內部信件
Attention B.F. Chalmers, Branch Manager.
主管經理B·F·查默斯收
With regard to recent and repeated correspondence,
鑒於近期頻繁反覆的通信
this is to advise that the matter has been
本人在此通告，該事項已經得到
very satisfactorily taken in hand, period.
完美的解決，句號
Paragraph. We wholly agree that the existing brochure is unsuitable.
另起一段，我們完全同意 現有的宣傳手冊內容很不合適
To this end, we have developed, quote,
為此，我們開發了
"Speaking of Production Control."
「關於生產控制的論述」
Here you go, Mrs Wheeler. These are the traveller's cheques you requested.
惠勒太太，這是您要的旅行支票
- Yes. - Your steamer reservations.
- 嗯 - 這是您預訂的汽船票
These I'll pass on to the embassy for you.
這些我會代為轉交大使館
- Good luck. - Thank you.
- 祝您好運 - 謝謝
September. October at the outside.
九月，最晚十月
I just happen to think people are better off
我只是覺得，我們該幹一些
doing some kind of work they actually like.
自己真正喜歡做的事情
- Right. Right, yes. - Absolutely, absolutely.
- 對，沒錯 - 的確
But, I mean, assuming there is this true vocation waiting for you,
但如果，假設說 這裡有一個好的職位給你
wouldn't you be just as likely to discover it here as there?
你難道也會拒絕？
I don't think it's possible to discover anything
我不覺得諾克斯大廈十五層
on the 15th floor of the Knox building,
可能發生什麼奇跡
and I don't think any of you do either.
在座各位應該也不會有這種想法吧
Daddy, Daddy, Daddy!
爸爸，爸爸，爸爸！
- Michael. - Daddy, will you read us...
- 邁克 - 爸爸，能不能給我讀…
...all the way to here.
…一直到這裡
We have to take a big boat ride across the sea to get there.
我們要坐一艘大船才能到那裡
- But I won't know anybody there. - I know. I know. Neither will I.
- 但那裡的人我都不認識 - 我知道，我也不認識
But remember how you felt when you started school?
但你記得剛上學時的感覺嗎？
And now look how many friends you have.
再看看現在，有多少朋友了
You'll never guess what they eat in Paris.
你怎麼也猜不到巴黎人吃什麼
- You'll never guess. - What?
- 不可能猜到 - 是什麼？
- Slimy snails. - Snails?
- 黏蝸牛 - 蝸牛？
Slimy snails and icky frog's legs.
黏蝸牛，還有黏青蛙的腿
Milly, where are you, doll?
米莉，你在哪兒寶貝？
You better get changed, they'll be here soon.
你最好去換衣服，他們馬上要來了
- Is that what you're wearing? - Don't you like it?
- 你就穿這個？ - 你不喜歡？
Yeah, yeah. You look great, doll.
嗯，很好看，寶貝
Guess I better haul ass.
看來我得趕緊了
Hiya, gang.
小子們
What you watching?
在看什麼？
Shep?
薛普？
I was calling you and calling you.
我一直在叫你
Hi.
你好
Here we go. Just a little something.
來了，一點小意思
- Those look great. I'm starving. - April, I can't get over it,
- 看起來不錯啊，我肚子開始叫了 - 艾波爾，我一直忘不掉
you look like the cat that ate the canary.
你看起來很滿足
Do you have something to tell us? Just a little bit of news?
你們是不是有事要告訴我們？ 一些新聞什麼的？
Well, actually, Milly, we... Well, we do have some important news, yes.
這個，米莉，我們…的確有很重要的消息
I knew it.
我就知道
Honey, why don't you tell them? Go ahead.
親愛的，你來說吧
We're going to Europe. To Paris.
我們要去歐洲了，去巴黎
To live.
搬過去
- What? - When?
- 什麼？ - 什麼時候？
- In September. - But what for?
- 九月份 - 為什麼呢？
What for? Well, because we've always wanted to.
為什麼？因為這是我們一直來的夢想
Because the kids are young enough. Because it's beautiful.
因為孩子們還小，因為那裡太美了
I mean, really. Shep, you've been there, you tell her.
薛普，你去過那裡，你說說看
- Yeah, it's a great city. - Yeah.
- 對，是個很棒的城市 - 是啊
When did you make this decision?
你們什麼時候決定的？
About a week ago? It's hard to remember.
大概一周前？記不清楚了
We just suddenly decided to go, that's all.
我們是突然決定的
- About a week ago, you tell us now. - We had to get used to the idea.
- 一周前決定，現在才跟我們說 - 我們也要一點時間來適應
So, what's the deal, Frank? You get a job over there, or what?
怎麼回事弗蘭克？ 你在那邊找了新工作還是怎麼的？
- No, no. Not exactly. - What do you mean, "Not exactly"?
- 不，不完全是這樣 - 什麼叫「不完全是這樣」？
Frank won't be getting any kind of a job, because I will.
弗蘭克不需要工作，我去上班
So what are you going to do, Frank?
那你做什麼，弗蘭克？
I'm going to study. And I'm going to read.
我要學習，讀書
I suppose I'm going to finally figure out what I want to do with my life, Shep.
我想我會弄清楚 我這輩子到底要做什麼，薛普
While she supports you?
你思考的時候她來養你？
Yes. While she supports me.
對，她來養我
In the beginning.
當然只是一開始
You wouldn't believe what they pay for secretarial work
你們猜不到政府給駐歐洲的秘書職位
in those government agencies over there.
什麼樣的薪水
NATO and ECA and those places.
北約啦，非洲經濟委員會之類的地方
And the cost of living is dirt cheap, right?
而且那裡生活成本真是低，對吧？
It's so cheap.
太低了
The truth is we just need something different.
說真的，我們只是希望有所改變
We're not getting any younger and we don't want life to just pass us by.
我們已經不再年輕，不想再浪費生命了
That's right.
沒錯
Gee, it sounds wonderful, kids.
天，聽起來太美好了
I mean it. It really sounds wonderful.
真的，太美好了
- Thank you, Milly. - Oh, Milly.
- 謝謝，米莉 - 噢，米莉
We'll certainly miss you both. Won't we, sweetie? Golly.
我們一定會想你們的，是吧？
- Sure. - We'll miss you, too.
- 當然 - 我們也會想你們的
- Of course. - True.
- 嗯
We should have a toast or something. To Paris.
我們是不是該碰一下，為了巴黎
- To Paris.
- 為了巴黎
- Cheers.
- 乾杯
You know what I think?
知道我怎麼想的嗎？
What?
什麼？
I think this whole plan sounds a little immature.
整個計劃有點不夠成熟
Oh, God, I am so relieved.
哦天，我真是鬆了一口氣
Me, too. I was thinking that the whole time.
我也是，我剛才也一直在想
I mean, what kind of man is going to sit around
什麼樣的男人願意整天穿著浴袍
in his bathrobe all day picking his nose
讓老婆在外工作
- while his wife goes out and works? - I don't know, Shep.
- 而自己坐在那兒摳鼻子？ - 對啊，薛普
I just don't know.
我真是不明白
Why are you crying?
你哭什麼？
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
It's nothing. I'm just so relieved.
沒什麼，就是放心了
Shep.
薛普
Don't cry. Please. It's all right. Everything's going to be all right.
別哭，沒事的，都會好起來的
My God, their faces! Oh, God.
天，看看他們的表情！哦天
Oh, God!
哦，天！
You know what this is like, April, honestly?
你知道這是什麼樣的感覺嗎，艾波爾？
Just talking like this?
說出這樣的話？
The whole idea of going off to Europe this way?
這搬到歐洲去的想法？
This is the way I felt going up to the line the first time, in the war.
我感覺就像第一場上戰場
I mean, I was probably just as scared as everyone else,
也許我和別人一樣害怕
but inside I never felt better.
但內心深處，卻從沒感覺這麼美好
I felt alive. I felt full of blood. I felt...
我覺得充滿活力，熱血澎湃…
Everything just... Everything seemed more real.
這一切…一切看起來更真實了
The guys in their uniforms.
那些穿著制服的傢伙
The snow on the fields, the trees. And all of us just walking.
田野裡的雪，還有樹上的雪 我們就這麼走著
I mean, I was scared, of course.
當然了我心裡害怕
But I just kept thinking, "This is it, you know. This is the truth."
但我一直在想 「沒錯，就是這樣，這才是生活」
I felt that way once, too.
我曾經有過這樣的感覺
When?
什麼時候？
The first time you made love to me.
第一次和你做愛的時候
April.
艾波爾
Frank.
弗蘭克
- What's up? - Bart Pollock's here.
- 怎麼了？ - 巴特·波洛克來了
He's in Bandy's office.
在班迪的辦公室呢
Big deal, huh?
有大事了，對吧？
Looks like he wants to talk to you.
看樣子他們要找你談話
Hey, keep my name out of it.
嗨，別把我扯進去
Frank. Good to see you. You know Bart Pollock?
弗蘭克，很高興見到你 認識巴特·波洛克嗎？
- Well, we've never met, but of course... - Good to know you, Frank.
- 我們沒見過，不過當然… - 很高興認識你，弗蘭克
"Speaking of Production Control"?
「關於生產控制的論述」？
Frank, this is a crackerjack.
弗蘭克，這真是神來之筆
They are tickled to death in Toledo.
托萊多那幫人非常滿意
Really?
真的？
So, this guy Pollock was perfect presidential material in the worst sense.
（《法國旅遊指南》） 沒有比這個波洛克更爛的老總了
A million dollar smile and about three pounds of muscle between the ears.
肥頭大腦，千金難博一笑
April, you should have heard this guy.
艾波爾，你真該聽聽他說的話
"Frank, this is a crackerjack." What a horse's ass.
「弗蘭克，這真是神來之筆」 真會拍馬屁
Wish I'd seen his face when you told him you were leaving.
不知道你說打算辭職的時候 他臉上是什麼表情
Yeah.
是啊
Here they come.
他們來了
- Sorry to be late. - You're not late.
- 抱歉來晚了 - 沒晚
- The traffic was terrible. - Thank you. You didn't have to do that.
- 街上太堵了 - 謝謝，真是太客氣了
- Good to see you. - Wasn't it terrible, Howard?
- 很高興見到你 - 太可怕了是吧，霍華德
Well, Route 12.
可不是，12號公路
By the time they finish that stretch of road,
估計等到路拓寬了之後
they'll have to start all over again, right?
照樣還是那麼堵
- And you must be John? - Say hello, John.
- 你一定是約翰了？ - 打招呼，約翰
Nice to meet you. Heard a lot about you.
很高興見到你們，久仰了
- Where are your darling children? - They're at a birthday party.
- 你們可愛的孩子們呢？ - 去參加生日聚會了
- Sorry they couldn't be here. - Don't worry.
- 很抱歉他們不在 - 沒關係
If I had a certified lunatic coming around my house,
如果知道有瘋子要來造訪
I'd probably get the kids out of the way, too.
我也會把孩子們送走
Look at all this food. You didn't have to go to any trouble for us.
看看這些吃的，沒必要這麼麻煩
It's just some sandwiches.
就是一些三明治
John, would you like a sandwich?
約翰，你愛吃三明治嗎？
Helen's been talking it up about you people for months.
幾個月來海倫一直在說你們
The nice young Wheelers on Revolutionary Road,
革命路上那對美滿的惠勒夫婦
- Would anyone like some sherry? - Please don't bother, Frank.
- 有人想喝雪莉酒嗎？ - 不用麻煩了，弗蘭克
I'd like some sherry.
我想要一些
And I'll drink Helen's, too, if she doesn't beat me to it.
海倫的那份也給我，如果她不搶走的話
But, hey, you got a high-ball glass?
你們有那種高玻璃杯嗎？
Put a couple-three ice cubes in it, pour it up to the brim.
放一些冰塊進去，然後再滿上
- That's the way I like it. - I think I can handle that.
- 我喜歡那樣 - 我應該能搞定
This egg salad is delicious, April. You must tell me how you fix it.
雞蛋沙拉真是太美味了，艾波爾 你一定得告訴我怎麼做
- You a lawyer, Frank? - No. No, I'm not.
- 你是律師嗎，弗蘭克？ - 不，不是
I could use a lawyer.
我想聘個律師
John, let's not get started again about the lawyer.
約翰，別再說律師的事了
Pop, couldn't you just sit there
爸，你就不能好好坐著
and eat your wonderful egg salad and quit horning in?
吃你的美味雞蛋沙拉，別廢話了？
See, I've got a good many questions to ask
是這樣的，我有很多問題要問
and I'm willing to pay for the answers.
而且也願意為此付錢
Now, I don't need to be told that a man who goes after his mother
不必你說我也知道 一個男人帶著一張咖啡桌
with a coffee table is putting himself in a weak position legally, that's obvious.
被老媽領著上街，是多麼讓人瞧不起 這很明顯
John, come and have a look out this fabulous picture window.
約翰，過來看看，外面風景多好
If he hits her with it and kills her, that's a criminal case.
但他如果用桌子砸死她，那就是犯罪了
- Oh, look, the sun's coming out! - Lf all he does is break the coffee table
- 看吶，太陽出來了 - 但他如果只是砸爛了桌子
and give her a certain amount of aggravation
又對著她發洩了一定量的怒火
and she decides to go to court over it, that's a civil case.
而她又打算起訴他，這就是民事案件了
Maybe we'll have a rainbow. John, come have a look.
也許還能看見彩虹呢，過來看看約翰
Ma, how about doing everybody a favour? How about shutting up!
媽，幫個忙好不，你就不能閉嘴？
Settle down, now.
坐下來吧
Maybe I can look into it, recommend someone. What do you say?
也許我能幫你問問，找個人 你看如何？
So, what do you do, Frank?
那麼你的工作是什麼，弗蘭克？
I work at Knox Business Machines, actually.
我在諾克斯商用機器公司上班
You design the machines?
你設計機器？
- Nope. - Make them, sell them, repair them?
- 不是 - 製造，銷售，還是維修？
- All these questions. - I help sell them, I guess.
- 這算什麼問題 - 我應該算幫著賣
I work in the office. Actually, it's...
我在辦公室上班，實際上呢…
Well, it's sort of a stupid job, really.
這個工作蠻傻的
There's nothing interesting about it at all.
毫無樂趣可言
What do you do it for then?
那你為什麼要做呢？
Maybe Frank doesn't like being questioned.
也許弗蘭克不喜歡被這麼糾纏著提問
Okay, okay, okay. I know it's none of my business.
沒事，沒事，我知道這不關我事
And besides, I know the answer.
不過呢，我知道答案
You want to play house, you got to have a job.
想要過家家，就得工作
You want to play very nice house, very sweet house,
想要在很好的房子裡過家家
then you've got to have a job you don't like.
你就得干你不喜歡的工作
Anyone comes along and says, "What do you do it for?"
要是誰來問，「你為什麼要做這工作？」
He's probably on a four-hour pass from the state funny farm.
那他也許是出來放風四小時的
- All agreed? Ma? - Sorry, Frank.
- 都同意吧，媽？ - 抱歉，弗蘭克
Don't be. Don't be. Actually, John, I agree with everything you just said.
沒事，沒事，實際上呢約翰 你說的我完全同意
We both do. That's why I'm quitting the job in the fall. We're taking off.
我們倆都同意，所以今年秋天 我要辭了這份工作，我們要走了
We're moving to Paris.
我們要搬到巴黎去
Did you know about this, Ma?
你知道這事嗎，媽？
How do you feel about that, Ma? The nice young Wheelers...
你怎麼想的，媽？年輕美滿的惠勒夫婦…
The nice young Wheelers are taking off.
年輕美滿的惠勒夫婦要搬走了
- John, please. - Steady down, Son.
- 拜託了，約翰 - 冷靜點，約翰
John. John. How about some fresh air? What do you say?
約翰，約翰，要不要呼吸點新鮮空氣？
If that's all right with you?
如果你不介意的話？
- I don't know if it's such a good idea... - lf John wants to, I don't see the harm.
- 我不知道這樣合不合適… - 如果約翰願意，那沒問題
- Good. - After you.
- 很好 - 你先請
- I hear you're a mathematician. - You hear wrong. It's all gone now.
- 我聽說你是個數學家 - 傳言有誤，都是過去的事了
All gone?
過去？
You know what electrical shock treatments are?
你聽說過電擊療法嗎？
Yes. Yes, I do.
嗯，聽說過
I've had 37.
我做過37次
Supposed to jolt out the emotional problems.
想要除去情感問題
- Just jolted out the mathematics. - How awful.
- 結果除去了數學知識 - 真可怕
"How awful"? Why, because mathematics is so interesting?
「真可怕」？為什麼，數學很有意思嗎？
No. Because the shocks must be awful and,
不，因為電擊太可怕了
well, because it's awful not to be able to do what it is that you want to do.
而且你就做不成你喜歡做的事了
I think mathematics must be dull.
我就覺得數學很無聊
I like your girl, Frank.
我喜歡你女人，弗蘭克
Me, too.
我也是
So, what do a couple of people like you have to run away from?
那麼，像你們這樣一對夫婦 到底要逃避什麼？
- We're not running. - So what's in Paris?
- 我們不是要逃避什麼 - 那巴黎有什麼？
- A different way of life. - Maybe we are running.
- 另一種生活方式 - 也許我們是在逃避
We're running from the hopeless emptiness of the whole life here, right?
我們是在逃避這充滿 令人絕望的空虛的生活，對吧？
The hopeless emptiness?
令人絕望的空虛？
Now you've said it. Plenty of people are on to the emptiness,
你還是說出來了 很多人都覺得空虛
but it takes real guts to see the hopelessness.
但發現絕望，還是需要勇氣的
Wow.
哇
You know, he's the first person
你知道麼，他好像是第一個
who seemed to know what we were talking about.
真正理解我們想法的人
Yeah. That's true, isn't it? Maybe we are just as crazy as he is.
的確，是吧？也許我們和他一樣癡狂
If being crazy means living life as if it matters,
如果癡狂的意思是過有意義的生活
then I don't care if we are completely insane.
那我不介意徹底瘋狂
Do you?
你呢？
No.
一樣
I love you so much.
我好愛你
Tell you something, Frank. That Ted Bandy, nice guy.
告訴你吧，弗蘭克 那個泰德·班迪人不錯
Real sport.
我很喜歡
Good enough department head and all.
作為部門領導，幹得很好
But I'm a little sore at him for the way he's kept you
但這麼多年來他一直讓你幹那些活
under a bushel all these years.
我就不大滿意了
- This place okay for you? - It's just fine, sir. Just fine.
- 這家店可以嗎？ - 很好先生，很好了
One thing interests me, Frank, and one thing only.
我只對一件事感興趣，弗蘭克，就一件事
Selling the electronic computer to the American businessman.
如何把電子計算機賣給美國商人
That's why I'm assembling a team. Men like you.
所以我在籌建一個小組，都是你這樣的人
Not your average salesmen.
而不是普通的銷售人員
It'll mean more money,
這意味著更豐厚的薪水
and, I got to be honest, maybe more of a time commitment.
不過老實說，也要花費更多的精力
But you'll be a part of something exciting, Wheeler.
但你會接觸到新鮮玩意，惠勒
Computers.
電腦
Well, sir, it sounds exciting.
聽起來很激動人心，先生
- Bart.
- 叫我巴特 - 巴特
Bart, let me ask you a question.
巴特，我想問你一個問題
Do you happen to remember an Earl Wheeler? Out of Yonkers?
你記得一個叫厄爾·惠勒的人嗎？ 在洋克斯市工作
- Can't say that I do. Relation of yours? - My father.
- 說實話不記得，你的親戚？ - 我父親
He worked as a salesman for Knox for almost 20 years.
作為一名銷售員，他為諾克斯公司干了20年
Earl Wheeler.
厄爾·惠勒
There's no reason you'd remember him.
當然你肯定不記得他
Well, I'm sure he was a good man.
這樣，我相信他是個好人
Listen, Bart, there's something I should have mentioned earlier.
聽著巴特，有件事我應該早就告訴你
I'm going to be leaving the firm in the fall.
我秋天就要從公司辭職了
- Another outfit? - No, no, it's not another outfit.
- 去別的公司？ - 不，不是跳槽
Now, look, Frank. Is it a question of money?
那告訴我，弗蘭克，是錢的原因嗎？
Because if it is, there's no reason
如果是的話，我們可以坐下來
we can't get together on a satisfactory...
談個很好的價錢…
Well, I sure appreciate that, but no, it's not the money.
我很感謝，不過不是錢的原因
It's... Well, it's more of a personal thing.
這…更多算是個私人問題吧
I hope you understand.
我希望你理解
A personal thing?
私人問題？
I see.
我知道了
Frank, let me tell you something my father told me.
弗蘭克，我跟你說一個我父親告訴我的道理
A man only gets a couple of chances in life.
人這一生，機會有限
If he doesn't grab them by the balls,
如果遇到的時候不緊緊抓住
it won't be long before he's sitting around wondering
那用不了多久，他就要開始自責
how he got to be second rate.
為什麼自己不如別人
I guess so.
我想是的
So, do me a favour. Sleep on it.
所以拜託，好好想想
Discuss it with your wife.
跟你老婆討論討論
Because let's be honest, where the hell would any of us be
說老實話，沒有了老婆
without our wives, anyway?
我們這些人又能從哪裡來？
And, Frank, in all sincerity, if you do decide to join us,
還有弗蘭克，我很誠懇的告訴你 如果你打算加入我們的小組
I believe it'll be a thing you'll never regret.
我相信你永遠也不會後悔
And I believe something else, too.
我還相信另外一點
I believe it'd be a fine memorial to your dad.
這絕對是對你父親最好的紀念
Think about it, Frank. Really think about it.
好好想想，弗蘭克，用心想
Knowing what you've got, comma,
清楚你有什麼，逗號
knowing what you need, comma,
清楚你需要什麼，逗號
knowing what you can do without, dash.
清楚你離不開什麼，破折號
That's inventory control.
這就是庫存管理
Knowing what you've got, comma,
清楚你有什麼，逗號
knowing what you need, comma,
清楚你需要什麼，逗號
knowing what you can do without, dash.
清楚你離不開什麼，破折號
That's inventory control.
這就是庫存管理
Hi, Frank.
你好，弗蘭克
Working late?
又加班？
Yeah. I got to dig myself out here.
對，我正在思考
I heard you were getting promoted.
聽說你要升職了
Big shot.
幹得好
I guess your dad would have been real proud, huh?
我想你父親應該為你驕傲，嗯？
Yeah. Yeah, I guess so.
嗯，我想會的
So maybe I should take you for a drink or something?
那麼我可以邀請你喝點什麼嗎？
You know, celebrate.
算是慶祝吧
Yeah, maybe.
嗯，也許可以
I'll just get my things.
那我去收拾一下
I'm going to bring my doll carriage
（此房出售） 我要帶上我的玩具馬車
and my three Easter rabbits and my giraffe
那三隻復活節兔子，長頸鹿
and all my dolls and my doll house and my crayons...
還有所有的娃娃，娃娃房，還有蠟筆…
I thought maybe we'd give the doll house to Madeline.
也許可以把娃娃房給瑪德琳
I don't want to give the doll house to Madeline.
我不想把娃娃房送給瑪德琳
But I already explained to you,
我都跟你解釋過了
the big things are going to be hard to pack.
那麼大的東西很難打包
But she can have my bear,
但可以把熊送給她
- and my three Easter rabbits. - No! Just the big things.
- 還有那三隻復活節兔子 - 不行！挑有用的
Look. Wouldn't you rather go outside and play with Michael?
你怎麼不出去跟邁克玩？
- I don't feel like it. - You've been inside all day.
- 我不喜歡 - 你整天都呆在屋子裡
I don't feel like it.
我不喜歡
Well, I don't feel like explaining everything 15 times
我也不喜歡都對著 又煩又傻又不聽話的小孩
to somebody who's too bored and silly to listen!
把每件事都解釋15遍以上！
- All right, April. What's the matter? - Nothing.
- 行了，艾波爾，怎麼了這是？ - 沒事
I don't believe you. Did something happen this morning?
我不信，今早發生什麼事了？
Nothing happened today that I haven't known about for days and days.
今天沒事，這麼久了我也不知道
What?
什麼？
Oh, God, Frank, please don't look so dense.
哦天，弗蘭克，別這麼詫異
You mean you haven't guessed or anything?
你難道一點也沒感覺出來？
April, what are you talking about?
艾波爾，你到底在說什麼？
I'm pregnant, that's all.
我又有了，就這樣
What?
什麼？
Frank, I meant to wait till the kids were in bed to tell you,
弗蘭克，我本想等孩子們都上床了再告訴你
but I just... Well, I've been pretty sure all week
但我…這幾天我已經差不多確定了
and today I went to the doctor,
然後今天我去看了醫生
and now I can't even pretend it's not true.
現在連我自己也不能假裝不知道了
- How long? - Ten weeks.
- 多久了？ - 十周
Ten weeks. Ten weeks? And you wait until now to tell me?
十周，十周？你現在才告訴我？
I thought... I don't know what I thought. I'm sorry, Frank. I'm so sorry.
我以為…我不知道我怎麼想的 很抱歉弗蘭克，對不起
I know. I know you are. All right?
我知道你很抱歉，好吧？
There are things we can do.
現在還不算晚
We don't have to let this stop us from going, do we?
這不會阻止我們離開的，對吧？
Remember that girl at school I told you about?
記得我告訴過你的那個女孩子嗎？
As long as we take care of it before 12 weeks, it's fine.
只要12周之前做掉，就沒問題
We've got to be together in this, Frank.
我們一定要齊心協力，弗蘭克
Well, we'll figure it out. All right?
會有辦法的，好嗎？
Come here.
過來
Twelve weeks. So we have time to decide, right?
十二周，那我們還有時間做決定，對吧？
Right.
嗯
I love you.
我愛你
I love you, too.
我也愛你
So, Frank, how's work? They gonna survive without you?
弗蘭克，工作怎樣？ 沒了你他們能幹的下去嗎？
Actually, something kind of funny happened the other day.
實際上呢，那天的事情很有趣
I did some dumb little piece of work to get myself off the hook with Bandy,
我就是耍了點小聰明 然後就逃離班迪的魔爪了
and suddenly, I'm the bright young man.
突然間，我成了一個聰明的年輕人
- That's always the way, ain't it? - It's incredible.
- 總有這種事，對吧？ - 真是不可思議
I mean, I knocked this thing off in a couple of minutes
我只花了幾分鐘寫出那些話
and now they want me to join their team of "specialist" salesmen.
現在他們要我加入什麼專業銷售組
Morons.
一群白癡
Well, it would be funny if they weren't offering
當然了，要是他們不提出那麼高的薪水
so much damn money.
那才見鬼了
So, are you tempted?
那你動心了？
Well, it's just kind of ironic, don't you think?
有點諷刺對吧？
I thought you turned the job down.
我以為你已經拒絕了
Not yet.
還沒
It's just an option, that's all.
只是個選擇，僅此而已
With the kind of money they're talking, things could be different for us here.
如果真拿到那份薪水，我們的生活會不一樣的
We could get a better place. Travel.
我們可以住得更好，可以旅遊
The point is, we could be happy here, at least for a little while.
關鍵是，我們能快樂起來，至少會快樂一陣子
It is possible that Parisians aren't the only ones
也許不只有巴黎人
capable of leading interesting lives, April.
能過上那麼有趣的生活，艾波爾
So you've made up your mind?
那麼你是決定了？
No. No. Like I said, it's just an option. That's all.
不不，都說了只是一個選擇，僅此而已
And supposing you're right.
就算你說的沒錯
You make all this money and we have this interesting life here.
你賺了很多錢，我們過得很開心
Won't you still be wasting your life toiling away at a job you find ridiculous?
那你還不是把生命都浪費在了 這份你覺得可笑的工作上？
Maybe we let that be my business, all right?
也許我自己操心這些就行了，好吧？
Your business?
你自己操心？
You know what? It's too hot for this. I'm going to go get wet.
太熱了，我得下水去
- You don't want to go, do you? - Come on, April. Of course, I do.
- 你根本不想走，對吧？ - 別這樣艾波爾，我當然想走
No, you don't. Because you've never tried at anything.
不，你不想，你就是貪圖安逸
And if you don't try at anything, you can't fail.
你如果不做嘗試，就談不上失敗
What the hell do you mean I don't try?
你說我不去嘗試是什麼意思？
I support you, don't I? I pay for this house.
是我養你，沒錯吧？房子是我買的
I work 10 hours a day at a job I can't stand.
我一天10小時幹那無聊的工作
- You don't have to. - Bullshit!
- 你沒必要這樣啊 - 狗屁！
Look, I'm not happy about it.
聽著，我是不喜歡
But I have the backbone not to run away from my responsibilities.
但我有骨氣，我清楚我自己的責任
It takes backbone to lead the life you want, Frank.
過自己想要的生活也需要骨氣，弗蘭克
Where are you going?
你去哪裡？
If it's all right with you, April, I'm gonna go use the bathroom. Okay?
如果你不介意的話，艾波爾 我想去下洗手間，可以嗎？
What the hell are you going to do with this?
你這是要幹嗎？
And what do you think you're going to do?
那你想怎樣？
- You're going to stop me? - You're damn right I am!
- 你要阻止我嗎？ - 他媽的說對了，我是要阻止你！
Go ahead and try.
你來啊
Listen to me. You do this, April, you do this and I swear to God I'II...
給我聽著艾波爾，你要是敢這樣 我發誓我會…
You'll what? You'll leave me? Is that a threat or a promise?
你會怎樣？離開我？這是威脅還是保證？
When did you buy this, April?
你什麼時候買的，艾波爾？
How long have you had this? I want to know!
你買了多久了？告訴我！
Jesus Christ.
老天爺
You really are being melodramatic about this whole thing.
你不要反應這麼劇烈好不好
As long as it's done in the first 12 weeks, it's perfectly safe.
只要是在十二周之內做掉，就完全安全
- That's now, April! Don't I get a say? - Of course you do!
- 那難道我就不能有我的意見？ - 當然可以！
It would be for you, Frank. Don't you see?
這是為了你好，弗蘭克，你看不出來嗎？
So you can have time, just like we talked about.
這樣你就能有自己的時間，像我們說好的那樣
How can it be for me when the thought of it
看在上帝的分上
makes my stomach turn over, for God's sake?
如果這事讓我覺得噁心，還能算是為我好嗎？
Then it's for me.
那算是為我自己
Tell me we can have the baby in Paris, Frank.
告訴我孩子會在巴黎出生，弗蘭克
Tell me we can have a different life. But don't make me stay here. Please.
告訴我生活會變得不一樣 但別讓我留在這裡，求你了
- We can't have the baby in Paris. - Why not?
- 我們不能在巴黎生孩子 - 為什麼？
I don't need everything we have here. I don't care where we live.
我不需要我們在這裡擁有的一切 我不在乎住在哪裡
I mean, who made these rules, anyway?
再說，有誰規定我們必須怎樣嗎？
Look, the only reason we moved out here was because I got pregnant.
我們搬來這裡，就是因為我懷孕了
Then we had another child to prove the first one wasn't a mistake.
之後我們又生了一個 來證明第一個孩子不是個錯誤
I mean, how long does it go on?
這到底何時是個盡頭？
Frank. Do you actually want another child?
弗蘭克，你真的還要一個孩子嗎？
Well, do you? Come on, tell me.
要嗎？來，告訴我
Tell me the truth, Frank. Remember that?
實話告訴我，弗蘭克，你還記得嗎？
We used to live by it.
我們一直很坦誠的
And you know what's so good about the truth?
你知道說實話的好處嗎？
Everyone knows what it is, however long they've lived without it.
大家都知道什麼是實話，但都避而不談
No one forgets the truth, Frank. They just get better at lying.
但沒有人能忘記事實，弗蘭克 他們只是越來越習慣撒謊
So tell me, do you really want another child?
請告訴我，你真的還想要一個孩子嗎？
All I know is what I feel.
我只知道自己的感覺
And anyone else in their right mind would feel the same way, April.
任何一個心智健全的人都會有這種感覺，艾波爾
But I've had two children. Doesn't that count in my favour?
但我已經生了兩個了，這還不夠嗎？
Christ, April! The fact that you even put it that way!
老天，艾波爾！你居然這麼想！
You make it seem as if having children is some sort of a goddamn punishment.
照你的意思，生孩子好像是他媽的受罪
I love my children, Frank.
我喜歡我的孩子，弗蘭克
And you're sure about that, huh?
你確定嗎，嗯？
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
你這話什麼意思？
April, you just said our daughter was a mistake.
艾波爾，你剛說了我們的女兒是個錯誤
How do I know you didn't try to get rid of her,
我怎麼知道你沒想過拋棄她
- or Michael for that matter? - No.
- 或者甚至是邁克？ - 沒有
How do I know you didn't try to flush our entire fucking family
我怎麼知道你沒想過把我們一家子
- down the toilet? - No, that's not true. Of course I didn't.
- 都衝進廁所？ - 不，不是的，我沒這麼想過
But how do I know, April?
但我怎麼知道，艾波爾？
Stop. Please just stop, Frank.
別這樣，拜託了別這樣弗蘭克
April, a normal woman, a normal sane mother
艾波爾，一個正常女人，一個心智健全的母親
doesn't buy a piece of rubber tubing to give herself an abortion
是不會為了想過他媽的幻想生活
so she can live out some kind of a goddamn fantasy.
而去買這種橡膠管
Look, all I'm saying is you don't seem entirely rational about this thing.
聽著，我只是想說 這整件事上你看起來都不是很理智
And I think it's about time we found somebody
現在是時候找個人來
to help make some sense of your life.
讓你的生活更有意義一點了
And the new job's going to pay for that, too?
你的新工作還能付得起這錢？
April, if you need a shrink, it will be paid for.
艾波爾，如果你需要精神醫生，那我掏錢
Obviously.
沒問題
Okay. I guess there isn't much more to say then, is there?
好吧，看來沒什麼可說的了，對吧？
So I guess Paris was a pretty childish idea, huh?
看來巴黎這事是挺幼稚的，對吧？
I guess maybe it was.
我想也許是吧
April, we can be happy here.
艾波爾，我們在這裡也能快樂
I can make you happy here.
我能讓你開心
We've had a great couple of months. It doesn't need to end.
在這裡的這些日子我們很開心 沒必要就這麼結束
We're going to be okay. I promise.
我們會沒事的，我保證
I hope so, Frank.
希望如此，弗蘭克
I really hope so.
我真的希望如此
Thank you for waiting. Mr Pollock will see you now.
久等了，波洛克先生可以見您了
Thanks so much.
多謝
Foiled by faulty contraception.
被意外的懷孕給攪黃了
I can't say that I'm sorry.
不得不為你感到遺憾
You'd have been sorely missed in the old cubicle, I can tell you that.
否則看到你的小工位，我們會想你的
Wouldn't have been the same without you.
沒了你一切都會變的
Besides... Well...
此外，嗯…
What?
怎麼？
The plan always seemed a touch unrealistic, don't you think?
你們的計劃看起來 總讓人覺得有點不切實際，對吧？
I suppose it's none of my business, really.
看來我多嘴了
No. No. I suppose it isn't.
的確，這是我們自己的事
Well...
那麼…
They'll be celebrating in the secretarial pool.
他們應該在秘書室慶祝過了
Hey! Remember the first time you brought us here?
嗨，記得你第一次帶我們來這裡嗎？
Absolutely.
當然
You said it takes a special kind of taste to enjoy Vito's Log Cabin.
你說一般人體會不出維多的小木屋的好
It's so awful, it's kind of nice.
太狠毒了，真好笑
Look at me. I'm just so happy. Our little gang's back together again.
看看，我真是太高興了 我們的小圈子終於不會解散了
- Hey, Europe's not going anywhere. - That's right.
- 反正歐洲又不會消失 - 沒錯
April, honey, how about a dance?
艾波爾，親愛的，跳個舞如何？
Not right now. Maybe later.
現在不想，待會兒吧
- I'll dance. - Okay.
- 我來跳 - 好
Guess she's still pretty blue about Paris, huh?
看來她還是忘不了巴黎，嗯？
Think she'll be okay?
她不會有事吧？
Sure. Give us girls a couple of days and we can get over anything.
當然，假以時日，都會忘掉的
Right.
對
Frank.
弗蘭克
Are you okay? Are you okay? Milly?
你沒事吧，米莉？
I'm so sorry.
抱歉
Excuse me.
失陪了
That's just great.
這下好了
How the hell are we supposed to get out now?
現在該怎麼出去？
Oh, boy.
哦天
Don't worry about it, Shep. We can wait. Really.
沒事，薛普，我們可以等著
What about the sitter?
那保姆呢？
Listen, why don't you drive Milly home, then go home yourself.
這樣，你帶米莉回去，然後自己回家
That takes care of both sitters. Then Shep can take me home later.
這樣兩家的保姆都能照看到 薛普一會兒送我回去
- Yeah, it's fine by me. - Okay, then.
- 嗯，我同意 - 那好吧
- You... You'll be all right? - Sure.
- 你…沒事？ - 當然
Okay.
好
- Good night.
- 晚安
Feel better.
趕快好起來
I'm sorry you're not going away any more.
很遺憾你哪裡也去不了了
I know it was important to you.
我知道這對你很重要
Don't take this wrong, but I've been there.
別誤會，不過我也去過那裡
They don't have so much we don't have here.
我們沒有的，他們基本也沒有
It didn't have to be Paris.
不是一定要去巴黎
You just wanted out, huh?
你就是想離開，對吧？
I wanted in.
我想回去
I just wanted us to live again.
我想回到我們自己的生活
For years, I thought we shared this secret.
這麼多年來，我以為我們心有默契
That we would be wonderful in the world.
我以為我們能過得很精彩
I didn't exactly know how, but just...
我不知道具體怎麼做，但…
Just the possibility kept me hoping.
我就是有這種信念
How pathetic is that?
很可悲是吧？
So stupid.
真傻
To put all your hopes in a promise that was never made?
把所有的希望寄托在從未許下的諾言上？
See, Frank knows. He knows what he wants.
不過弗蘭克很清楚，他知道自己想要什麼
He's found his place. He's just fine.
他找到了自己的位置，所以安心了
Married, two kids.
結婚了，生了兩個孩子了
It should be enough.
這就已經夠了
It is for him.
對他來說如此
And he's right.
他是對的
We were never special or destined or anything at all.
我們是普通人，注定這麼過一輩子
Yes, you are.
不，你們不普通
You're...
你們是…
You're the Wheelers.
你們是惠勒夫婦
You're a terrific couple. Everybody says so.
你們是多美滿的一對，大家都這麼說
I saw a whole other future.
我看到了另一種未來
I can't stop seeing it.
我止不住去憧憬
Can't leave,
走不了
can't stay.
也留不住
No damn use to anyone.
廢物一個
Come on.
來吧
Let's do it.
跳支舞
Let me take you somewhere.
我帶你去別的地方
No. Just do it here. Now.
不，這裡就行了，來吧
April.
艾波爾
This is what I've always wanted.
這是我一直想要的
I love you.
我愛你
Don't say that.
別這麼說
No. I mean it, I love you.
不，我說真的，我愛你
Please, just be quiet for a minute.
求你了，安靜一會兒
Then you can take me home.
然後帶我回去
It's beautiful out.
天氣不錯啊
Yes, it is.
沒錯
You know what today is?
知道今天什麼日子嗎？
- It's 12 weeks. - That's right.
- 十二周了 - 沒錯
Look, this has been kind of a crazy summer.
這個夏天可夠瘋狂的
We've both been under a strain.
我們壓力都很大
I mean, I understand why you're upset.
我是說，我知道你為什麼不安
You know I'm not sleeping with you, and you want to know why.
你知道我沒和你睡，你想知道為什麼
Well, I'm sorry, Frank, but I really don't feel like talking about it.
對不起，弗蘭克，我真的不想說這些
All right. Then what should we talk about, April?
好吧，那我們聊點什麼，艾波爾？
Would it be all right if we didn't talk about anything?
什麼也不說可以嗎？
I mean, can't we just take each day as it comes, and do the best we can,
我的意思是，迎接每一天的到來 盡力做好自己的事，可以嗎？
and not feel like we have to talk about everything all the time?
不要總覺得我們該聊點什麼
I don't think I'm suggesting that we talk about everything all the time.
我好像沒有要一直聊天的意思吧
Look, my point is we've both been under a strain
聽著，我的意思是我們倆壓力都很大
and we ought to be helping each other out as much as we can right now.
現在應該盡力幫助對方
I mean, God knows my own behaviour has been pretty weird lately.
我最近的舉止可能有些奇怪
As a matter of fact, there is something I'd like to tell you about.
實際上呢，我想和你說件事
I've been with a girl a few times, in the city.
我和一個女孩好過幾次，在城裡
A girl I hardly even know.
一個我幾乎不瞭解的女孩
It was nothing to me,
逢場作戲而已
but it's over now, really over.
已經過去了，真的
And if I weren't sure of that, I guess I could never have told you about it.
如果我不確定的話，我應該是不會告訴你的
Why did you?
你為什麼這麼做？
Baby, I don't know.
寶貝，我也不知道
I think it's a simple case of wanting to be a man again
也許很簡單，流產的事情之後
after all that abortion business.
我想再一次成為男人
Some kind of neurotic, irrational need to prove something.
有一種很變態的需求要證明什麼
No. I don't mean why did you have the girl.
我不是說你為什麼有了外遇
I mean, why did you tell me about it?
我是說你為什麼跟我說這些？
- What do you mean? - I mean, what's the point?
- 你什麼意思？ - 你到底想表達什麼？
Is it supposed to make me jealous or something?
是想要我嫉妒還是怎麼著？
Is it supposed to make me fall in love with you,
是想讓我再次愛上你
or back into bed with you, or what?
再和你上床，還是怎麼著？
I mean, what would you like me to say, Frank?
你到底想讓我說什麼，弗蘭克？
Why don't you say what you feel, April?
你為什麼不說說自己的感受，艾波爾？
I don't feel anything.
我沒什麼感受
In other words, you don't care what I do or who I fuck or anything?
換句話說，你不在乎我做了什麼 不在乎我干了誰，什麼都不在乎？
No, I guess that's right. I don't.
也許是吧，我不在乎
Fuck who you like.
愛干誰幹誰
April, don't you understand that I want you to care?
艾波爾，難道你不明白我需要你在乎我？
I know. I know you do.
我明白，我知道你需要
And I suppose I would if I loved you.
我想如果我愛你的話，我是會在乎你的
But I don't think I do any more. And I only just figured that out.
但我應該不再愛你了，我剛剛才想明白
And that's why I'd just as soon not do any talking right now.
所以我不想再說什麼了
Don't give me that shit, April. Don't give me that.
別跟我說這些屁話，艾波爾，少來這套
- You know goddamn well you love me. - You think so?
- 你他媽心裡是愛我的 - 你真這麼覺得？
You know goddamn well!
你他媽心裡清楚！
Anyone home?
家裡有人嗎？
I'm sorry dinner's late. Would anyone like another drink?
抱歉飯還沒好，還有人要喝點什麼嗎？
Don't worry. It's nice to just sit a bit and socialise.
沒事，坐坐聊聊挺好的
You shouldn't have gone to all this trouble.
沒必要搞這麼麻煩
With all your packing and whatnot.
東西應該都收拾好了
I imagine you have a lot on your plate. No pun intended.
現在應該只有盤子可以用了吧 說笑而已
Actually, there's been a change of plans.
實際上計劃有所變動
I thought maybe it was obvious.
我還以為很明顯呢
April here is pregnant.
艾波爾懷孕了
- Congratulations. - Oh, April!
- 恭喜啊 - 噢，艾波爾
I can't tell you how pleased I am!
知道我有多高興嗎！
But I expect you'll be needing a bigger house now, won't you?
看樣子你們需要一間大一點的房子了，對吧？
Hold it a second, Ma. Hold on a second, Ma.
等等，媽，等一下
I don't get this. I mean, what's so obvious about it?
我不明白了，有什麼明顯的？
I mean, okay, she's pregnant, so what? Don't people have babies in Europe?
她是懷孕了，但又怎樣呢？ 難道歐洲人就不懷孕了？
- John... - Suppose we just say
- 約翰… - 這麼說吧
that people anywhere aren't very well advised to have babies
不管哪裡的人，如果供養不起
unless they can afford them.
一般是不會要孩子的
Okay. Okay, it's a question of money. Money's a good reason.
好吧好吧，是錢的問題，錢是個好理由
But it's hardly ever the real reason.
但這從不是真正的原因
What's the real reason? Wife talk you out of it or what?
到底是為什麼？老婆說服你不去了？
Little woman decide she isn't quite ready to quit playing house?
小女人覺得她還是過家家比較好？
No, no, that's not it. I can tell.
不不，應該不是，我看得出來
She looks too tough and adequate as hell.
她看起來很堅決的樣子
Okay, then. It must've been you. What happened?
那應該是你的問題了，怎麼了？
- John, please. You're being very rude. - No, no. What happened, Frank?
- 拜託約翰，你太粗魯了 - 不不，怎麼了，弗蘭克？
You get cold feet?
你害怕了？
You decide you're better off here after all?
你覺得還是在這裡好？
You figure it's more comfy
你覺得還是守著這
here in the old hopeless emptiness after all, huh?
令人絕望的空虛生活比較好，嗯？
Oh, wow, that did it. Look at his face.
猜對了，看看他的臉
What's the matter, Wheeler? Am I getting warm?
怎麼了，惠勒？被我說中了？
- All right, Son. I think we'd better be... - You know something?
- 夠了兒子，我看我們還是… - 知道不？
I wouldn't be surprised if he knocked her up on purpose
如果說他是故意讓她懷孕
just so he could spend the rest of his life hiding behind a maternity dress.
從而能夠安穩的過一輩子 我一點也不奇怪
That way he'd never have to find out what he's really made of.
這樣他就用不著去尋找真實的自我
Now look, I think that's just about enough out of you.
行了，我看你也說夠了吧
I mean, who the hell do you think you are?
你他媽的以為自己是誰？
You come in here and say
你到我家來
whatever crazy goddamn thing comes into your head,
滿口胡言亂語，說話不經大腦
and I think it's about time somebody told you to keep your goddamn mouth shut.
我看該是有人讓你閉上臭嘴的時候了
- He's not well, Frank. - Not well, my ass!
- 他有病，弗蘭克 - 有屁個病！
I don't give a damn if he's sick or well or dead or alive,
我可不管他是有病是活著還是死了
he should keep his fucking opinions
他這些狗屁廢話
in the fucking insane asylum where they belong!
就該他媽的留到精神病院去說！
- Let's go, Son. - Come on, John.
- 我們走，兒子 - 走吧，約翰
Big man you got there, April.
你老公很猛啊，艾波爾
Big family man.
大男人
I feel sorry for you.
我為你感到遺憾
Still, maybe you deserve each other.
不過，也許你們還真是配
I mean, the way you look right now, I'm beginning to feel sorry for him, too.
看到你這樣子，我也開始為他感到遺憾了
You must give him a pretty bad time
如果靠造人才能證明自己是真男人的話
if making babies is the only way he can prove he's got a pair of balls.
你一定讓他很不好過
- You fucking... - No! He's not well, Frank!
- 你媽個… - 別這樣！他病了，弗蘭克
All right, John. Let's get on out to the car now.
好了約翰，我們走吧
April, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
艾波爾，對不起，真的對不起
Oh, right. Sorry. Sorry! Sorry!
噢對，對不起，對不起，對不起！
Ma, have I said "I'm sorry" enough times?
媽，我說夠「對不起」了嗎？
Damn! I am sorry, too.
操！我是很可悲
I bet I'm just about the sorriest bastard I know.
我可能是我認識的最可憐的王八蛋了
But get right down to it, I don't have a whole hell of a lot to be glad about.
不過話說回來 我他媽的也沒有什麼可高興的
Do I?
是吧？
But, hey, you know what?
不過你知道不？
I am glad about one thing.
有件事我很高興
You want to know what I'm glad about?
知道我高興什麼嗎？
I'm glad I'm not gonna be that kid.
我高興我不是那孩子
Okay, okay, don't tell me.
好吧，別告訴我
Don't tell me, let me guess.
別告訴我，讓我自己猜
I made a disgusting spectacle of myself, right?
我大出洋相了，對吧？
Right.
嗯
And everything that man said is true, right?
那男的說的都是對的，是吧？
Is that what you're going to say?
你是不是想這麼說？
Apparently I don't have to.
很明顯我沒必要說
- You're saying it for me. - Well, you're wrong, April.
- 你都替我說了 - 那你錯了，艾波爾
- Really? Why am I wrong? - Because the man is insane.
- 是嗎？我為什麼錯了？ - 因為那男的瘋了
He's fucking insane! Do you know what the definition of insanity is?
他他媽的瘋了！ 你知道瘋了是什麼意思嗎？
No. Do you?
不知道，你知道？
Yes, it's the inability to relate to another human being.
是的，就是無法和別人正常交往
It's the inability to love.
就是無法去愛
April. April.
艾波爾，艾波爾
April! April!
艾波爾！艾波爾！
The inability... The inability to love.
沒法去…沒法去愛
Frank. You really are a wonderful talker.
弗蘭克，你真能忽悠
If black could be made into white by talking,
如果想把死人說活
you'd be the man for the job.
那你再適合不過了
So now I'm crazy because I don't love you. Right?
所以我瘋了，因為我不愛你，對吧？
- Is that the point? - No. Wrong.
- 你是不是這個意思？ - 不是
You're not crazy and you do love me. That's the point, April.
你沒瘋，你愛我 我是這個意思，艾波爾
But I don't. I hate you.
但我不愛你，我恨你
You were just some boy who made me laugh at a party once
你只是一個在酒會上博我一笑的男孩
and now I loathe the sight of you.
現在我再也不想看到你
In fact, if you come any closer, if you touch me or anything,
如果你再靠近，如果你碰我或怎樣
I think I'll scream.
我會喊的
Come on. Stop this, April.
別這樣，行了，艾波爾
Fuck you, April!
我操你媽，艾波爾！
Fuck you and all your hateful, snotty little...
我操你媽個…
What're you going to do now? Are you going to hit me?
你現在想怎樣？想打我？
- To show me how much you love me? - Don't worry, I can't be bothered!
- 來表達你有多愛我？ - 被擔心，我不會自找麻煩
You're not worth the trouble it would take to hit you.
你根本不值得我打你
You're not worth the powder it would take to blow you up.
你根本不值得我發脾氣
You're an empty, empty, hollow shell of a woman!
你是個空虛的女人！
What the hell are you doing in my house if you hate me so much?
你要是這麼恨我，為什麼還在我的房子裡？
Why the hell are you married to me?
為什麼還要嫁給我？
What the hell are you doing carrying my child?
為什麼還要懷我的孩子？
I mean, why didn't you just get rid of it when you had the chance?
你早幹嘛不做掉他？
Because listen to me. Listen to me, I got news for you.
聽我說，聽我說，我他媽告訴你
I wish to God that you had.
我真希望你做掉了
April!
艾波爾！
- April! - Stay away from me.
- 艾波爾！ - 別靠近我
- April, listen.
- 聽我說，艾波爾
Can't I even get away from you in the fucking woods?
我他媽的在樹林裡也躲不了你嗎？
April, listen, I didn't mean that.
聽著，艾波爾，我亂說的
- Honestly, I didn't mean what I said. - Are you still talking?
- 真的，我不是有意的 - 你還要說是吧？
Isn't there any way to stop your talking?
你就不能閉嘴嗎？
I need to think. Can't you see that? I need to think.
我要冷靜一下，你看不出來嗎？ 我要冷靜一下
Please come back to the house. What're you doing out here, April?
先回屋裡去吧 你在外面幹什麼，艾波爾？
Do you want me to scream again, Frank?
你是不是要我再喊，弗蘭克？
Because I will! I mean it!
我會的！我說真的！
Okay. Okay.
好吧，好吧
Good morning.
早上好
Would you like scrambled eggs or fried?
你要炒雞蛋還是荷包蛋？
I don't know.
不知道
It doesn't really matter. Scrambled, I guess, if it's easy.
無所謂了，炒吧，如果這樣容易
Fine. I'll have scrambled, too.
好吧，我也吃炒的
It's kind of nice having breakfast without the kids for a change, huh?
沒有小孩在，吃早飯真開心，是吧？
Yes.
嗯
I thought you'd probably want a good breakfast today.
我想你今天也許要吃頓好的早飯
I mean, it's kind of an important day for you, isn't it?
今天對你來說很重要，對吧？
Isn't this the day you have your conference with Pollock?
今天不是要和波洛克開會嗎？
Yes. Yes, that's right.
對，沒錯
- Big deal. - I imagine it is a pretty big deal.
- 大事啊 - 我想應該是挺大的事
For them, anyway.
不過是對他們而言
What exactly do you think you'll be doing in your new job?
你這新工作到底要做什麼？
You haven't really told me much about it.
你還沒跟我仔細說過
Haven't I?
沒有嗎？
Well, I think this whole thing is about Knox getting ready
其實整件事呢，就是諾克斯公司
to buy up one of those really big computers,
打算買一台那種大型計算機
even bigger than the 500.
比500型還要大的那種
- Didn't I tell you about that? - No.
- 我沒跟你說過？ - 沒
Why don't you tell me now?
不如現在告訴我？
Well,
是這樣
you know, basically it's just a big, fast adding machine.
實際上呢，這是個很大，很快的加法器
Only, instead of mechanical parts, you see,
只不過原先使用的機械零件
you've got thousands of individual vacuum tubes.
被替換成了成千個真空管
I see.
明白了
At least I think I see.
至少我覺得明白了
Yes, it's really kind of interesting, isn't it?
這真有意思，是吧？
Well, I don't know.
我也不知道
Yeah, I guess it is kind of interesting, in a way.
也許從某方面來說，是有點意思吧
You should value what you do, Frank.
你應該重視你的工作，弗蘭克
You're obviously good at it.
很顯然你在行
Well, I guess I'd better be getting started, huh?
那麼我也許該走了？
Listen, though, April, the...
聽著，艾波爾…
This was really nice.
這樣真的很好
I mean, it was a swell breakfast. Really, I...
我是說，很好的早飯，我真的…
I don't know when I've ever had a nicer breakfast.
我不記得什麼時候吃過這麼好的早飯了
Thank you. I enjoyed it, too.
謝謝你，我也很滿足
Then you don't... You don't hate me or anything?
那你不…不再恨我了？
No. No, of course I don't.
不，當然不會
Have a good day.
祝你順利
Okay, then. So long.
那好，再見了
Hello. Milly? Everything all right?
你好，米莉？都還好吧？
Well, no, I'm afraid I'm not feeling any better. That's really why I called.
我好像並沒有好轉，所以我才打給你
If it's not an inconvenience for you, this evening would be great.
如果方便的話，今晚就可以
What?
什麼？
Oh, no. No. Not if they're outdoors playing.
噢不，他們要是在外面玩就算了
No.
不用了
Don't call them in.
別把他們叫進來
Just give them each a kiss for me,
替我親親他們倆
and tell them I...
然後告訴他們我…
Tell them...
告訴他們…
You know. All right. All right. Thank you, Milly. Bye.
你知道了，好，謝謝，再見
I think I need help.
我需要幫助
115 Revolutionary Road.
革命路115號
- Frank. They tell you what happened? - Jesus Christ.
- 弗蘭克，他們都告訴你了？ - 老天啊
Shep, I didn't understand half the things he told me.
薛普，他們說的我都沒大聽懂
He said the foetus was out before they got her here.
他們說到家的時候胎兒已經出來了
And they had to operate to take out the, what do you call it, the placenta?
然後他們只好手術取出那個什麼，胎盤？
And now she's still bleeding.
然後現在還在出血
He said that she'd lost a lot of blood before the ambulance came,
他說救護車到的時候已經流了很多血了
and now they're trying to stop it.
他們現在在想辦法止血
He said a whole lot of things I didn't understand about capillaries...
他說了一堆什麼毛細血管之類的東西…
He said that she's unconscious. Jesus.
他說她昏迷了，老天
Okay, Frank, why don't you just take a seat?
好了，弗蘭克，你先坐下吧？
What the hell do I want to sit down for, for God's sake?
我他媽的為什麼要坐下？
Okay, Frank. Just take it easy. Take it easy.
放鬆點，弗蘭克，放鬆點
- Frank, have a cigarette. - She did it to herself, Shep.
- 來根煙，弗蘭克 - 她自己動手的，薛普
She did it to herself.
她自己動手的
I'm gonna get you some coffee.
我去給你來杯咖啡
They were such wonderful people. Weren't they, Shep?
他們真是美滿的一對，是吧薛普？
It's just devastating. Poor April.
太可怕了，可憐的艾波爾
Thank you.
謝謝
Frank lives in the city now. Where is it that he works?
弗蘭克現在住在城裡了 他在哪裡工作來著？
- Bart Pollock Associates. - Computers?
- 巴特·波洛克聯合公司 - 電腦？
Interesting firm.
有意思的公司
- Have you seen him since? - No. Not back here.
- 你有沒有再見到他？ - 沒，沒回來過
There are too many memories, I think. Shep has seen him in the city.
我想那裡有太多回憶了 薛普在城裡見過他
Haven't you, sweetie?
是吧，親愛的？
Frank is just devoted to those kids.
弗蘭克現在全心撫養孩子了
Every spare moment he has, he spends with them.
一有時間就陪著他們
Excuse me.
失陪一下
You all right?
你還好吧？
I don't want to talk about the Wheelers any more.
我不想再談論惠勒夫婦了
Okay.
好
We don't have to.
沒必要談
Daddy, Daddy, watch. Watch, Daddy.
爸爸，爸爸，看啊爸爸
I can't tell you how pleased I am
革命路上的那間小屋子
about the little Revolutionary Road place, Howard.
我真的很滿意，霍華德
And now whenever I drive past, it gives me such a lift
每次路過那裡，看到一切都再次井然有序
to see it all perked up and spanking clean again.
和諧安寧，我就很欣慰
All the lights in all the windows.
看看屋裡透出的那些亮光
And do you know? I was just thinking, I've loved that little house for years.
知道嗎？我剛在想 我對這小房子鍾愛了這麼多年
And the Braces are the only really suitable people I've ever found for it.
佈雷斯夫婦是我找到的最適合它的主人
Really nice, congenial people, I mean.
真的很友善，很美滿的一對
Well, except for the Wheelers, you mean.
你是說除了惠勒夫婦
I was very fond of the Wheelers.
我很喜歡惠勒夫婦
They were a bit whimsical for my taste. A bit neurotic.
不過在我看來他們有點古怪，神經質
I never stressed it, but they were often
我從沒和人這麼說過
very trying people to deal with, in many ways.
不過很多時候，他們讓我很討厭
And actually, the main reason that the little house was so hard to sell
當然了，這小屋子這麼難賣掉
was because they let it depreciate so dreadfully.
就是因為他們讓它迅速貶值了
Warped window frames, wet cellar, crayon marks all over the walls,
扭曲的窗框，潮濕的地下室，佈滿塗鴉的牆壁
filthy smudges around the door knobs and the fixtures...
還有門把上、衛生間裡的污點…